A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry, 2008-2018 (bulk 2014-2018)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry, 2008-2018 (bulk 2014-2018)
The Library of Virginia
52174
8 cu.ft. (16 boxes)
Virginia. Office of the Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Privacy protected and confidential information is restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Restricted records in this collection have been sealed but not removed from the collection. Types of sealed information may include, but are not limited to: attorney-client communications and proprietary records.
Acquisition Information
Transferred on 10 January 2018 by the Office of the Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry, 1111 East Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, 23219.
Historical Information
Finally established in 2004, the eventual creation of the Agriculture and Forestry secretariat began with a 2001 gubernatorial campaign promise made by Governor Mark R. Warner to provide cabinet level representation for the agriculture and forestry industry. Further support for the creation of the secretariat came from the Governor's Agriculture Net Receipts Work Group, a task force created in 2003 by Governor Warner through the Secretary of Commerce and Trade. The goal of the task force was to determine strategies and recommendations for doubling the net profits of Virginia's agricultural sector between 2004 and 2014. Among the task force's recommendations was the creation of the, "Office of Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry to provide focus and emphasis in the development of the agriculture and forest industries." In 2004, the General Assembly of Virginia created the cabinet position of Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry with the passing of Senate Bill SB 543 and witnessed its codification through 2.2-203.3 of the Code of Virginia. Speaking at the appointment ceremony of the first Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry, Governor Warner reiterated his commitment to, "support and expand our agriculture and forestry industries" and recalled his desire to, "make sure these very important sectors of Virginia's economy received a seat at my cabinet table."
The Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry is appointed by the Governor, confirmed by the General Assembly, and serves at the Governor's pleasure. It is the secretary's responsibility to oversee several agencies and other entities that formerly reported to the Office of the Secretary of Commerce and Trade. Among the agencies reporting to the Agriculture and Forestry secretariat are the Virginia Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, the Department of Forestry, the Virginia Agricultural Council, and the Virginia Marine Products Board. The Governor may assign or reassign agencies to and from the Agriculture and Forestry secretariat through the use of executive orders. The secretary's role in leading agencies within the Agriculture and Forestry secretariat is to provide guidance and direction, "in the conservation, protection, and development of Virginia's agricultural and forest resources and in protecting the Virginia Consumer."
Todd Haymore served as the Virginia Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry from 2010 until 2016 September. Basil Gooden served as Virginia Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry from 2016 September until 2018 January.
Scope and Content
Records, 2008-2018 (bulk 2014-2018), created and maintained by Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry, Todd Haymore (2010-2016) and Basil Gooden (2016-2018), during the administration of Governor Terry McAuliffe (2014-2018). The records include agendas, correspondence, memorandum, minutes, newspaper clippings, presentations, programs, reports, speeches, studies, and other working papers.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Agriculture and Forestry Industries Development (AFID) Fund, 2010-2016
Series II: Correspondence: Assigned State Agencies, 2010-2017
Series III: Correspondence and Supporting Documentation, Office of the Secretary, 2008-2018
Series IV: Economic Development, 2009-2016
Series V: Public Relations, 2010-2018.
Contents List
- Series I: Agriculture and Forestry Industries Development (AFID) Fund, 2010-2016., Extent: 5 boxes (1.75 cu. ft.). (Box 1-5)
  Series I: Agriculture and Forestry Industries Development (AFID) Fund, 2010-2016, is housed in five boxes. This series includes agendas, announcements, brochures, budgets, correspondence, meeting notes, memorandum, project lists, and reports. The series is divided into three subseries: General, Locality, and Company Name. The General subseries includes budgets, guidelines for the fund, and project lists. The Locality subseries are arranged alphabetically by locality and contain grants reviews, grant applications, and letters of support. The Company Name subseries are arranged alphabetically by company name and contain announcements, correspondence, event briefing information, and talking points.
  The Governor's Agriculture and Forestry Industries Development (AFID) Fund is a discretionary, performance-based economic development incentive specifically for agriculture and forestry value-added or processing projects. The AFID program supports agribusinesses of all sizes including produce companies, dairy processors, meat and poultry processors, specialty food and beverage manufacturers, greenhouse operations, forest product manufacturers and more. The fund can also support aquaculture projects such as oyster production and nurseries producing native plants for stormwater BMPs. An AFID facility grant is awarded to a political subdivision for the benefit of the company, with the expectation that the grant is critical to the success of the new or expanding facility. The grant amount and terms are determined by the Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry and approved by the Governor.
  - General
    - Agriculture export numbers, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Brochures, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Guidelines and Best Practices, 2012-2013 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Guidelines and Best Practices, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Meeting notes, 2010-2011 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Meeting notes, 2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Monthly update, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Performance agreement, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Project lists, 2012-2015 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Project pipeline (old), 2016 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Two-year report, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Weekly report, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Locality
    - Abingdon, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Albemarle County, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Buckingham County, 2013-2014 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Buckingham County, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Essex County, 2013-2014 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Fauquier County, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Franklin City, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Franklin County, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Giles, Montgomery, and Pulaski Counties, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Halifax County, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Highland County, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - James City County, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Northern Neck, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Prince Edward County, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Rappahannock-Rapidan Region, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Region 2000 Agricultural Strategic Plan, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Roanoke County, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Central Shenandoah, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Shenandoah County, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Staunton, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Surry County, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Company Name
    - AgVets, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Andros Foods NA, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Big Trouble Malting and Spirits, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Blacks Hops Farms, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Bloomaker, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bowman Andros, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Bright Farms, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Charlottesville Food Hub, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Copper Fox, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Dan River Plants, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Deschutes Brewery, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - El Rosal, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Ferrum College, 2013-2014 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Franklin Lumber, 2013-2014 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Greencore Group, 2013-2014 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Hansen/Falcon Turbine, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Hardywood, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Homestead Creamery, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Ironclad Distillery, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Montague Farms, 2013-2015 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Old House Distillery, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Oyster Trail, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Pilot Malt House, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Purcellville Viticulture Center, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Red Sun, 2014 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Red Foods, 2014 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Route 11 Potato chips, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Seven Hills Food LLC, 2014-2015 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Shamrock Farms, 2014 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Shenandoah Growers, Inc., 2015 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Shenandoah Processing, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Stone Brewing Co., 2014-2015 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Trae Fuels Ltd., 2013 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Tranlin Inc., 2014-2015 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Trout River Dry Kiln, LLC, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Turman Lumber, 2013 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Twenty Paces-Kelly Turkeys USA, LLC, 2015 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Vireol Bio Energy, LLC, 2012-2014 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Poultry Growers Cooperative, 2015 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Produce, 2013 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Series II: Correspondence: Assigned State Agencies, 2010-2017., Extent: 5 boxes (1.75 cu. ft.). (Box 6-10)
  Series II: Correspondence: Assigned State Agencies, 2010-2017, is housed in five boxes and arranged alphabetically by folder title. This series includes agendas, budgets, correspondence, notes, and reports. This series includes information relating to issues concerning the agencies under the Secretary including Virginia Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, the Department of Forestry, and the Virginia Racing Commission, among others. The series is further divided into two subseries: General and Constituent Cases.
  - General
    - Animal shelters, 2017 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Board appointments, 2014-2017 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Broadband, ca. 2017 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Budget (2016-2018), 2015 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Cabinet on the Road, 2014 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 2017 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Chesapeake Day Commission, 2017 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, Resource Management Plan, 2017 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Dept. of Forestry, Board of Forestry, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Dept. of Forestry, Board recommendations, 2016-2017 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Dept. of Forestry, Budget (2018-2020), 2017 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Dept. of Forestry, Forest mitigation, 2017 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Dept. of Forestry, Statement of need, 2017 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Dept. of Forestry, Timber theft, 2017 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Dept. of Forestry, Wilderness-Stuart Inc and Mountain Top Logging, LLC, 2016 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Dept. of Forestry, Virginia Rural Center, Board of Directors Meeting, 2014 June (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - General Assembly, 2017 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Governor's Cabinet Exercise, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Issues, 2017 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Annual reports, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Avian influenza, 2017 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Charities, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Coyote control, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Fauquier Livestock Exchange, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Food programs, 2015 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, FSA Loan Subordination 2011 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Hemp, 2017 (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, IT issues, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Legal cannabis, 2017 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Legislation, 2016 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Legislative charitable gaming, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Milk Commission, 2017 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Office of Consumer Affairs, 2011-2012 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Pesticide examinations, 2011-2012 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Reduced ignition propensity cigarettes, 2012-2013 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Small AFO Evaluation and assessment strategy, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Strategic planning, 2014, 2017 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Va. Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Weights and measures, 2011 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Virginia distillers, 2016 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Racing Commission, General, 2014, 2017 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Racing Commission, Meeting, 2014 September 17 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Racing Commission, Meeting, 2014 October 15 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Racing Commission, Meeting, 2015 July 29 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Wine Distribution Company, 2012-2014 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Waters of the United States, 2014-2017 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Constituent cases
    - Atlantic Red Crab Co., nd (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Bath County: George Washington National Forest, 2010-2011 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Bosh Group, ca. 2012 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Chesapeake Bay: Certainty, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Chesapeake Bay: McDonnell, nd (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Chesapeake Bay: Partnership Principal Staff Committee, 2012 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Chesapeake Bay: Watershed Fairness Act, 2012 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Chinese log ban, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Conservation easements, nd (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Education, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Enterprise strategic priorities, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Fauquier County: Right to Farm, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Fauquier Farm Winery Ordinance, 2012 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Grape cost share, 2013-2014 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Grayson Land Care, 2013 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Green Trees, 2014 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Hammock Dairy Pond, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Litter to Energy, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Lumber Liquidators, 2012 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Mennel-West Point Projects, 2013 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - NASA Develop, 2013 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Richmond Ballet, 2014 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - SAF (Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry): Consolidation of Water Programs, 2012-2013 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - SAF: Northern Neck Food Bank, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - SAF: ReEnergy, nd (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - SAF: RFS Waiver, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - SAF: SWCD Summer Study, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - SAF: SWCD Summer Study, 2013 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Trump: VOF (Virginia Outdoors Foundation) Easement, 2013 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - VACS (Virginia Agricultural Cost Share): BMP Manual, 2015 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Land Conservation Foundation, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Series III: Correspondence and Supporting Documentation, Office of the Secretary, 2008-2018., Extent: 11 boxes (3.85 cu. ft.). (Box 11-21)
  Series III: Correspondence and Supporting Documentation, Office of the Secretary, 2008-2018, is housed in eleven boxes and arranged alphabetically by folder title. This series includes agendas, brochures, clippings, correspondence, event briefing information, house bills, memorandum, notes, press releases, reports, and speeches. The series is further divided into two subseries: Events and Subject files.
  - Subseries A: Events
    Subseries A: Events, 2015-2017, is housed in four boxes and contains agendas, briefing information, programs, press releases, notes, and speeches pertaining to events attended by the Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry. A variety of events include bill signings, trade missions, opening of agricultural related stores, conferences, visits by Ambassadors of other countries, AFID announcements, agritourism conferences, rotary club dinners, among others.
    - Virginia Agritourism Conference, 2015 March 10-11 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Cuba trade and marketing mission, 2016 January 3-6 (Box 11, Folder 1a-4)
    - Shawnee Canning Co., 2016 January 8 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Ambassador Gonzalex-Revilla (Panama), 2016 January 8 (Box 11, Folder 5a)
    - Cider meeting, 2016 January 11 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - West Richmond Businessmen Association, 2016 January 11 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - VADO Day on the Hill, 2016 January 14 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Agribusiness Council, 2016 January 14 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - VAC Legislative Dinner, 2016 January 14 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - VEDA Day on the Hill, 2016 January 19 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Eastern Shore Agricultural Conference, 2016 January 26 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - VFBF Legislative reception, 2016 January 27 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Virginia Biological Farming Conference, 2016 January 29 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - VIVA Grower of the Year, 2016 January 29 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Monroe Bay Vineyards, 2016 February 1 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Ambassador Cabanas (Cuba), 2016 February 2 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Rural Caucus, 2016 February 3 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Wildland Firefighters, 2016 February 4 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Ambassador Baganez (Mexico), 2016 February 8 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Ambassador Al-Jaber Al-Sabah (Kuwait), 2016 February 8 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Ambassador Al Mughairy (Oman), 2016 February 8 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - USACC Annual Celebration, 2016 February 10 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Ambassador Tiankai (China), 2016 February 12 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Ambassador Malmierca (Cuba), 2016 February 15 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Grain and Soybean Conference, 2016 February 17 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - 4-H Foundation luncheon, 2016 February 17 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Blue Bee Cider, 2016 February 18 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Ambassador Anderson (Ireland), 2016 February 18 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Ambassador Dermer (Israel), 2016 February 18 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Distillers Association, 2016 February 18 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Hampton Rhoads Winery, 2016 February 18 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Reservoir Distillery, 2016 February 19 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Governor's Cup, 2016 February 22 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Governor of Jeollanamdo (S. Korea), 2016 February 24 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - VAC Emerging Agribusiness Leaders Lunch, 2016 February 25 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Minister Kawazu (Japan), 2016 February 25 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Stone VIP Media opening, 2016 February 25 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - GMU Global Trade Class, 2016 February 29 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - VTC Baby goat filming, 2016 March 1 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - RSA Cyber Conference Marketing Mission, 2016 March 2-4 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Lansing Trade Group meeting, 2016 March 7 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Governor's Conference on Agricultural Trade, 2016 March 7-8 (Box 12, Folder 23-24)
    - Halifax County AFID, 2016 March 9 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - NYC-VTC Mission, 2016 March 14-16 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - VEDA Spring Conference, 2016 March 18 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Century Farm-Forest Event, 2016 March 21 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Deschutes Brewery Event, 2016 March 22 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Loudoun Co. Chamber of Commerce, 2016 March 24 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Agritourism Conference, 2016 April 6 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Beyond Brewing, 2016 April 7 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Embassy of Japan, 2016 April 7 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Ambassador Pinzon (Columbia), 2016 April 7 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Ferrum College, 2016 April 11 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - West Richmond Rotary Club, 2016 April 13 (Box 13, Folder 10a)
    - University of Richmond, Pi Sigma Alpha Dinner, 2016 April 13 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Hampton Roads Winery, 2016 April 14 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Richmond Forum, 2016 April 15 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - VCU eMBA Class, 2016 April 15 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - The Veil Brewing Co., 2016 April 15 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Woodgrain Millwork AFID, 2016 April 18 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Virginia Forest Summit, 2016 April 20 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Rotary Club of Innsbrook, 2016 April 21 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Hargrave Military Academy, 2016 April 21 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Steward School Children COOP, 2016 April 21 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Hannover Messe & Europe Marketing Mission, 2016 April 23-29 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Craft Brewers Conference, 2016 May 3-6 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Cabinet on the Road, 2016 May 6 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Richmond Kiwanis Club, 2016 May 9 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Boston & Canada Mission, 2016 May 17-20 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Trinity Methodist Church, 2016 May 22 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Farm Credit of the Virginias, 2016 May 23 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Virginia International Business Council, 2016 May 23 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - USDA-FAS-LES Tour, 2016 May 25 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Showalter Orchard Love Unveiling, 2016 June 1 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - VTC Board Meeting, 2016 June 2 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Bill signing, 2016 June 3 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Gregory Lumber, Inc., 2016 June 8 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Danville-Pittsylvania County Chamber of Commerce, 2016 June 8 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Asian Chamber of Commerce, 2016 June 9 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Isley Brewing, 2016 June 13 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - US Global Leadership Coalition, 2016 June 13-14 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Budget Roll Out-Pittsylvania County, 2016 June 21 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Virginia Vine, 2016 June 24 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Bristol (Va.) visit, 2016 June 29-30 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Handsome Brook Farms, 2016 June (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Israel and Farnborough Airshow Marketing Mission, 2016 July 8-13 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Secure Commonwealth Panel, 2016 July 13 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Tangier Oyster Region, 2016 July 21 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Project Sweetie dinner, 2016 July 28 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - International Trade Budget Rollout, 2016 August 2 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Ag Expo, 2016 August 4 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - CCAM Board meeting, 2016 August 4 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - KO Distilling AFID announcement, 2016 August 16 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Appalachian Mountain Spirits, 2016 August 16 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Virginia Loggers Association Annual meeting, 2016 August 27 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Sabor USA, 2016 August 28-September 3 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Dept. of Forestry, Budget Rollout, 2016 August 29 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Craft Beer Month, 2016 August 29 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Stone Brewery Brew Day, 2016 August 30 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Port City Brewing Co. AFID Announcement, 2016 August 31 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - T & E Meats AFID Announcement, 2016 September 1 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - General Assembly Session, ca. 2016 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Agricultural Trade Conference, 2016-2017 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Subseries B: Subject files